Guide to the River Oaks Business Women's Exchange Club Records
University of Houston Libraries
River Oaks Business Women's Exchange Club Records
1977-2007
1977-2002
02/2006-007
River Oaks Business Women’s Exchange Club
6.00 Linear Feet
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
The collection is housed in 3 boxes and 2 drawers and is organized into 10 series entitled: Organizational Documents, Roster/Year Books, Newsletters, Photographic Works, ROBWEC Anniversaries, Invitations and Greetings, Clippings, Correspondence, Notes, and Ephemera.
Historical Note:
River Oaks Business Women’s Exchange Club or ROBWEC was formed on February 12, 1976 when fewer than ten business and professional women met for the first time in the Travel Lodge. It was the idea of Marilyn Elam, a recent law school graduate who had moved to Houston to take a federal district court law clerkship. The small group of women continued to meet informally until July 2, 1976, when Jeanne Atherton moved the meetings to the River Oaks Country Club and officially organized the River Oaks Business Women’s Exchange Club. The plan was quickly implemented to recruit women of professional strength and power, each a leader in her field in the greater Houston area.
The purpose of ROBWEC is to bring together businesswomen of the city of Houston. This business and professional women's organization meets monthly for networking opportunities and business support. ROBWEC provides its members with web access to the membership directory, a monthly newsletter, special interest groups, and socials. Members interact with other business and professional women and hear informative speakers who educate, inspire, and entertain. From its humble beginnings in 1976, ROBWEC now has nearly one hundred members representing dynamic and diverse backgrounds and occupations.
Access Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Corporate Name:
River Oaks Business Women’s Exchange Club
Genre/Form of Material:
Correspondence; Newsletters; Photographs; Typescripts
Geographic Name:
River Oaks (Tex.)
Topical Term:
Business networks -- Texas -- Houston; Businesswomen -- Texas -- Houston; Women -- Societies and clubs
Conditions Governing Access:
Open for research.
Acquisition Information
Information of acquisition method not available.
Scope and Contents
The collection is housed in 3 boxes and 2 drawers and is organized into 10 series entitled: Organizational Documents, Roster/Year Books, Newsletters, Photographic Works, ROBWEC Anniversaries, Invitations and Greetings, Clippings, Correspondence, Notes, and Ephemera. The bulk of the material documents the organization’s operations and events of the club. Some materials are contained in map drawers which are located in the back corner of the stacks.
Detailed List of Contents
- Organizational Documents
  Scope and Contents
  This section houses Information with regard to the organization from the time of its inception in 1977. The meeting records of the organization are compiled together.
  - ROBWEC History (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Constitution and By-laws (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Duties and Responsibilities (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Guidelines and Applications (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Meeting Records, 1978-1981 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Meeting Records, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Meeting Records, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Meeting Records, 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Meeting Records, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Meeting Records, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Meeting Records, 1992-1995 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Meeting Records, 1997-2000 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Meeting Records, 2001-2002 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Meeting Records and Miscellaneous, 2003-2006 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Meeting Records, 2006-007 (Box 1, Folder 14a)
- Rosters/Year Books
  This series houses the year books and membership information of ROBWEC.
  - Year books (Bound) 1993-1996 (Box 1, Folder 15-17)
  - 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - 1980-1998 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - 2000-2001 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Membership Classifications (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 22-26)
  - Directory, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Directory, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Member Biographies (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Newsletters, 1977-2006
  - 1977-1979 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 1985 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 1988 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - 1989-1997 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - 1998-2000 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - 2001-2002 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 2003-2004 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 2005-2006 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Photographic Works
  Photographs pertaining to the various ROBWEC parties and anniversary celebrations.
  - Prints (Box 3, Folder 1-3)
  - Images on disc (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - 20th Anniversary, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Hat Day, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - 1997 (Drawer F.1, Ovs folder 1)
    - Christmas Party (Drawer F.1, Ovs folder 1, Item 1)
    - Hat Day (Drawer F.1, Ovs folder 1, Item 2)
- Anniversaries
  Five year anniversary celebrations and publicity material form part of this series.
  - 1981, 1986 and 1991 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - 1996 and 2001 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Invitations and Greetings
  Consists of printed invitations to events both ROBWEC and others. Also included are greeting cards for various occasions.
  - Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 10-11)
- Clippings
  Newspaper clippings describing women empowerment, news regarding ROBWEC or other organizations of its like.
  - Clippings, mostly undated (Box 3, Folder 12-15)
- Correspondence
  General business correspondence and membership correspondence are housed in this series.
  - Membership, 1977-1992 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Membership, 1993-1996 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Membership, 1998-2001 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - General (Box 3, Folder 19-20)
- Notes
  - Notes (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Ephemera
  This series contains oversized materials related to ROBWEC. The series includes a deconstructed scrapbook of organization presidents and exhibition boards.
  - Presidents' Scrapbook, undated (Drawer F.1, Ovs folder 2)
  - Timeline Exhibition Board, 1977 (Drawer F.1, Item 1)
  - Timeline Exhibition Board, 1981 (Drawer F.1, Item 2)
  - Timeline Exhibition Board, 1988 (Drawer F.1, Item 3)
  - Timeline Exhibition Board, 1992 (Drawer F.1, Item 4)
  - Timeline Exhibition Boards, 1979 (Drawer F.2, Item 1)
  - Timeline Exhibition Boards, 1983 (Drawer F.2, Item 2)
  - Timeline Exhibition Boards, 1986 (Drawer F.2, Item 3)
  - Timeline Exhibition Boards, 1990 (Drawer F.2, Item 4)
  - Timeline Exhibition Boards, 1994 (Drawer F.2, Item 5)
  - Timeline Exhibition Boards, 1996 (Drawer F.2, Item 6)